No one betrays me!
I'd say we just proved
that's not true.
Nokt?
-[whooshes]
-[Ras] Ah!
[growls]
[Sora, Lloyd grunt]
Yah! [grunts]
[gunfire]
[straining]
[grunts]
-Yah!
-[clangs]
-[gunfire]
[grunts]
Let me tell you something,
going from having
half the Elemental Powers
in the Tournament
to absolutely none? [grunts]
-Not ideal.
-[both grunt]
Arin told me the dragon horns
are at that strange Monastery.
[grunts] I would have
bet everything
Ras was behind this.
I was so wrong.
[both grunting]
Don't be so hard on yourself.
Jordana being taken over
by an ancient evil soul
was not something anyone
factored into the equation.
We gotta keep Nokt and Rox
from getting to that Monastery
to free the rest
of the Forbidden Five!
It might be too late for that!
Get back here!
Those Elemental Powers
belong to me!
[roars]
[grunts]
[gunfire]
[grunting]
I knew Lloyd wouldn't listen
when I told him Master Wu
caused the Merge.
I just knew it!
Arin, that information
is a lot to process.
What's to process?
Your teacher disrupted
all the realms!
He caused
my parents to disappear!
[Cole grunting]
Ugh! These things
are welded on tight!
The games are almost over,
Cole.
And if Ras wins,
he'll be here in a split second
to use these horns to get
to the Source Dragons.
-We gotta hurry!
-[crash]
-Did you hear that?
[crash]
Be prepared for anything.
[grunts]
-[Riyu warbles]
-Nya!
-[laughs]
-This is most unexpected.
Tell me about it.
Riyu and I found a way
to talk to Kai.
Riyu gives me a spark,
and my connection
with my brother
lets me use some dragon ivory
to speak to him.
Dragon ivory like
from those horns?
[Nya] Exactly! Apparently,
Dragon Crowns
can communicate
with the Nether-Space,
and could be our key
to freeing Kai and Bonzle.
But unfortunately, could
also free the Forbidden Five.
How did you determine
all of this?
We overheard it when
we were being captured by--
[gasps] Them!
♪ Lost in the unknown
So much to see ♪
- ♪ Together we will rise! ♪
-♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a Ninja
For what's right! ♪
[flames roaring]
[Cole]
Ninja, go!
Yah!
[grunts]
You're not getting
to the Source Dragons!
Ras's plans end now!
Source Dragons? Ras?
This has nothing
to do with them!
This is all us.
[laughs evilly]
[grunts]
[growls]
This is not how I envisioned
our partnership ending,
Lord Ras.
Partnership? Ha!
-But I thought we were friends!
-[grunts]
[grunts]
Why you gotta
cramp my space?
The Gamesmaster
is the only one
who can use the Element Cup.
You alone have to drain Nokt
of the powers he stole.
Mega agree,
but don't think this means
I forgot you tried
to hijack my games.
Uncool, Ras. Way uncool!
No! Ras has Roby!
They're probably
heading to Nokt,
which is what
we should be doing!
[sighs] But we're needed here!
[Frak] Go after Nokt!
We can handle this!
[grunts] I fought bullies
long before I became
Master of Quake. Hah!
Yah! There's more to us
than elemental powers.
You sure, Frak?
Ninja, go.
You're just wasting our time!
[Rox yells]
[Rox, Nokt grunt]
Rising Dragon Technique
says otherwise.
I sincerely detest
Rising Dragon.
Forget them. Go summon
the rest of the Five, brother.
[grunts]
Brother?
[attack yell]
Aah!
[screeches]
Shatterspin's not
the only fighting skill
I can perform with this body--
[groans]
Stop! I'm in control! Not you!
[groaning]
[as Jordana]
Ninja, get out of here!
I don't know how long
I can stop Rox!
What's happening to you?
I can't hold her! Get away!
[grunting]
[attack yell]
Ha!
Frozen in place!
No one can defeat us!
[groans]
At last, we will be free.
At last, all the merged realms
will fall beneath our might!
[rumbling]
Surprise!
[yells]
[Nokt] Aah!
Wow, true Spinjitzu
really is way more powerful.
Do you really think
you have a chance at--
Aah!
Next time, I drive.
[warbles]
Frak taught you
my techniques well.
You have achieved
proper Spinjitzu, Arin.
Hopefully you knocked him out.
Be much easier to drain--
Ah!
Flank him!
[grunts]
Roby! Now!
You've really crushed
my vibe, Nokt.
Games are supposed
to be fun, dude.
Look it up.
[roars]
Aah!
The Forbidden Five will enjoy
crushing you two first!
[both scream, grunt]
[groans]
[rumbling]
Come to me, my brethren!
You are finally free!
[explosions]
[laughs] Master after master,
village after village,
army after army,
all crushed by the Five.
Imagine the sheer
delusional ego needed
to believe you could sto--
Ah!
[groans]
Okay, what was that?
[zapping]
[gasps]
Rox! Good to see you, sister!
The real you.
[groans] Ninja. While Rox
puppeted my body,
I was trapped inside her mind.
I've seen her thoughts,
her evil plans.
You've got to stop her!
Why aren't you doing anything?!
Would love to, but--
Oh! The static spell!
-Ahh.
-Yes!
Let's go. Can you
make a new bridge, Cole?
[grunts, groans]
This mech doesn't have any
more Elemental energy in it!
We have to find
another way across.
[engine approaches]
We can help with that!
[grunting]
[warbles]
[Ras groaning]
[Arin grunts]
You would help me, Ninja?
Look, we're not buddies
or anything,
but you know
where my parents are.
I know a great many things,
Arin.
I know the truth
about this universe.
-[strains]
-[thuds]
I just want to find my parents.
[Nokt] Did they
not survive the crossing?
[Rox] They're alive. Just
drained by the corrupted method
that we used to breech
the Nether-Space.
I too feel the strain.
We must get away,
somewhere to recover.
[Lloyd] Sorry!
Vacation plans cancelled!
You get your hands off my--
Hey, where's Roby?
[Lloyd]
Ninja, go!
[grunts with effort]
[grunting]
Yah!
All of you? Bah!
I've never been more powerful!
Bring it on!
[fighting grunts]
Aah!
How did you learn
perfect Spinjitzu?
Not from you.
[Cole grunts]
[whimpering] Ah!
[gasping]
Wyldfyre! Thank you!
No prob.
It wasn't even a big deal
because I didn't have
to overcome
a crippling fear
of heights to do it.
[grunts] I'll be the stang
to your zoot anytime.
[roars]
What was that?
A romance roar.
In my culture,
the fire dragons,
that's how we declare love.
Roar!
Did... did I do that right?
-[both roaring]
-[crash]
Come on! We gotta
get you and your Element Cup
back up there. Somehow.
[intense music]
[fighting grunts]
[strains]
Ah!
[reverberates]
[crashing]
[roars]
[grunts]
That's for thinking
the Forbidden Five
would be pawns
in your game, Ras!
We own the game!
[Arin]
No! Don't hurt him!
Ah!
[grunting]
[warbles]
-What, Riyu? What--
-[warbles]
What about the horns?
-[gasps]
Of course! My connection
through the dragon ivory!
What are you doing?! Stop!
Don't you dare touch her!
That's my sister!
-[gasps]
-Kai!
Yeah!
[cracks neck]
[fighting grunts]
[reverberates]
Nah, I know that trick.
I don't need Shatterspin
to stop you, Ninja!
Yah!
But I now have more Elemental
Powers than anyone in history!
Now, this is just annoying.
[grunting]
Ah!
[grunts]
I think I'll finish you
with your own student's
heat power.
A poetic end to the Red Ninja.
Wha--
No one ends the Red Ninja.
Sorry, Nokt, had
to transfer your powers.
It happens to all the losers.
[Nokt gasps]
In the name
of the Source Dragons,
I honor the grand tradition
of the games
by returning
all Elemental Powers
to their rightful owners!
[whooshing]
[epic music]
Woohoo!
[screeching]
[gasps]
It cannot, will not,
end like this!
[Rox]
Nokt! Come on!
[Ras]
You'll pay for your betrayal--
[Nokt]
No! You shall pay!
My revenge on you
is not yet complete!
No! I need him!
Arin, no! Wait!
Arin, stop!
[explosion]
Arin! Arin!
[Lloyd]
They-- They all got away.
And they've got Arin.
Arin chose to go with them.
So, I see nothing exciting
has been happening
since I've been gone.
[Wyldfyre]
Aww!
[groans, laughs]
So good to have you back, bro.
Bonzle, it's good to see you.
But seriously,
perfect entrance, you two.
[whooshes]
Master Wu?
Never in the history
of the Tournament of Sources
have we seen
anything like this.
Betrayal by one sworn
to protect the games--
but never before have we seen
such brave, noble competitors
who defended
the honor of the games,
and the lives
of their colleagues.
[audience cheering]
And though a winner
was already declared,
as Gamesmaster,
I officially void that victory.
Told you my games
would be unprecedented!
[cheering]
I now declare the true winner,
the greatest Elemental Master
in all the Merged Lands:
Sora: The Elemental Master
of Technology!
[cheering]
This really is an
extreme victory extravaganza!
Thank you, again.
We couldn't have done it
without you!
Has anyone seen Jordana?
No, not since she
stopped Rox's static spell.
If she didn't try to break
through Rox's control
and get me those clues,
we wouldn't have
solved this mystery.
I wanted to thank her.
I'm surprised she
doesn't want to talk
to the Greatest Elemental
Master in the Merged Lands.
Remember when you
used to insist
you didn't have
an Elemental Power?
[chuckles] Feels like
a million years ago.
I know you had your doubts
about being our Master,
but I couldn't have done this
without you, Lloyd.
You and Arin inspire me.
He and I had a falling out
during the tournament.
Since the Merge, I--
I've never been
without my best friend.
We'll find him. I promise.
But what if he doesn't
want to be found?
So, uh, I was wondering,
do you really have to go?
Um, uh, as much
as I wanna stay,
and trust me,
I really want to stay,
all the other Ninja
are helpless without me.
I have to go back.
But we'll stay in touch?
Absolutely. I'll never forget
our first roar.
[roars]
Roar!
[both roaring]
Uh, Wyldfyre?
Time to go, cutie.
How are we getting home?
Our dragons left
a long time ago.
Well, we have a new way
to get to the Monastery.
[Riyu panting, warbles]
He didn't remember me.
Or any of us.
No matter what I told him.
Well, wherever Jay went,
you and I are gonna
track him down
and knock some sense into him.
I talked to the Cloud Monks.
Arin and the others
didn't come out of the gate
in the Cloud Kingdom.
I was afraid of that.
The explosion may have
scattered them
to anywhere
in the Merged Lands.
[whooshes]
You came!
I'm-- I'm so sorry.
Sorry for what, Conduit?
I failed you.
Your mission was
to discover those responsible
for the death
of the Matriarch.
You have done that.
Yes, but the Forbidden Five
got away.
With their plans disrupted,
and more importantly,
you stopped another mortal
from using
the combined
Elemental Powers
to get to us Source Dragons.
The entire Counsel
will now surely recognize
that the danger
from the mortal world is real.
So, maybe, we did succeed.
Do not doubt yourself,
Conduit.
One of your students won
the Tournament of Sources.
You Ninja have proven
to be most worthy
of the gifts of
the Source Dragons.
The Source Dragons now owe
the Conduit a great debt.
And we always pay our debts.
-[clangs]
-[Lloyd gasps]
[Motion Source Dragon]
More than a mere weapon,
that is a Dragon icon.
A what?
With this, you have the right
to summon me
to the mortal world... once.
Use it only
when you truly need me.
[whooshes]
[flames whoosh]
You were right,
the Ninja failed me.
Master Wu, who
taught them everything,
is the reason
my parents are gone.
I'm gonna help you get better,
Ras.
And then, you're gonna
lead me to my parents.
Because now you're the only one
I believe can do that.
[intense music playing]